H-O-I-V-L
H-O-I-V-L.
Hoilv
Hoilv.
Vlohi
Vlohi.
Hovil  不对  那不是单词
Hovil. No. That's not a word, either.
你真的一整夜没上床睡觉
Did you seriously stay up staring at this scrabble board
就盯着这拼字板看吗
all night instead of going to bed?
我得用剩下的这五个字母
With these five remaining tiles,
拼出一个单词  就能得9分
I have to craft a word scoring 9 points,
那我就能反败为胜了
and I turn defeat into victory.
天呐  你真的赢过我爸了
Oh, my gosh. Did you really beat dad at scrabble?
我可没承认  我要再倒点咖啡去
I concede nothing, except that I need more coffee.
你可真了不起
That is quite an accomplishment, young lady.
从来没人能赢他呢
Nobody beats him -- ever.
对啊  这话他总挂在嘴边
Oh, yeah. He's mentioned that... repeatedly.
真可惜  伟人都失手了呢
Ahh, how the mighty have fallen. Mm.
"理查德·卡塞尔  败于某单词"
"Richard castle. One word short."
我不能让这话成为我的墓志铭
I cannot allow this to be my epitaph.
偷着点乐呗
I saw that.
好吧  我承认败给你了  谢谢
Okay, I'll admit defeat Thanks.
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
我已经赢你了你还"让"我赢
You're letting me win after I already won.
不过我们今晚得再比一次
Under the condition that we have a rematch tonight.
瞧瞧你又在修改投降条款
Oh, wow. Now you're dictating the terms of surrender.
你直接说接不接受吧
Take it or leave it, please.
发生了什么
So, what happened here?
据我们的...证人说
Well, according to our... witness,
这个叫罗根·摩尔的死者
our victim, one Logan Moore,
当时正踩着滑板逃命
was hauling ass on a skateboard
后面有个骑摩托车的人在追他
with a guy on a motorcycle chasing him.
听着像是动作片里的场景
Sounds like a scene from an action movie.
对啊  特别是后来摩托车手开枪
Yeah, I know, especially when the biker started shooting
而罗根摔下了那边那扇窗子
and Logan crashed through that window right there.
死者身上有没有什么线索能解释这一切呢
Anything about our victim that'll explain what happened?
还没有  只知道他21岁  持有加州驾照
Not yet -- just that he's 21, has a California driver's license.
这是我们目前找到的所有线索
About all we got at this point.
那目击证人能描述这位摩托车手吗
So, this biker -- was our witness able to give a description?
证人宿醉未醒
Our witness is royally wasted.
他只知道大约3点到4点间
All he knows is that sometime between 3:00 and 4:00,
这儿上演了一段《夺命狂奔》
it was "Death race 2000" Out here.
证据显示他说的是对的
The evidence backs him up, too.
鉴证组在那片泥土上发现了清晰的轮胎印
CSU found fresh tire tracks in that dirt over there.
现在他们正在做模型
They're making casts as we speak.
那么这要么是史上最残忍的驾驶暴怒
So either this is the worst case of road rage ever
要么就是有人决心杀死罗根·摩尔
or someone was hell-bent on killing Logan Moore.
但为什么呢
But why?
为什么他凌晨3  4点间在外玩滑板呢
And why was he out skateboarding between 3:00 and 4:00 a.m.?
如果他是要呼吸新鲜空气的话  那他如愿了
Well, if he needed some fresh air, he got some --
因为他后背打通了三个孔
by way of three holes in his back
用的是9毫米口径的中空弹
from .9mm hollow-points.
凶手情况不详
So, no eyes on the shooter.
这片区域没有安装监控摄像头
There's no security-cam coverage in this area.
死者不是本地人
Our victim's from out of town,
他肯定得找个地方住
so he had to have been staying somewhere.
你找到酒店钥匙或者收据了吗
Did you find a hotel key or a receipt?
确实在他脖子上找到了这把钥匙
Well, we did find this key hung around his neck
他口袋里有这张纸片
And this scrap of paper in his pocket.
上面写着西格林威治的一个地址
It's a west village address.
你和埃斯波西托去查这个地址
You and Esposito check that out.
我和卡塞尔去找找死者的线索
Castle and I will see what we can find out about our victim.
能等我一会儿吗
Can you just hang on for one second for me?
蕾妮  裙子你抽空试穿了吗
Hey, Lanie. Were you able to schedule the fitting for your dress?
当然
Absolutely.
你帮我挑的那条裙子简直太赞了
And the dress that you picked out for me is gorgeous.
是高雅和俏皮的完美结合啊
It's the right mix of elegant and saucy.
我当然得小心伺候我的伴娘大人啦
Well, I had to do right by my maid of honor.
-好了  我得走了  回见  -好
- Okay, I got to go. I'll see you. - All right.
-嘿  蕾妮  -嘿
- Hey, Lanie. - Hey.
我俩没听错吧
So, did we hear right?
你是贝克特的伴娘吗
Are you Beckett's maid of honor?
对啊  前几天她来跟我讲的
Yeah, she asked me the other day.
那你知道卡塞尔的伴郎是谁吗
Do you have any idea who Castle's best man is?
首先  该说"恭喜啦  蕾妮"
First, "Congratulations, lanie."
多谢
Oh! Thank you!
其次  我不知道卡塞尔选伴郎了没啊
Second, I don't know if he's picked anyone yet.
你俩真觉得他会在你们中选一个
You...really think it's one of you?
你们啊
You two.
面对现实吧
Reality of it is,
卡塞尔有好些名人朋友
is that castle's friends with famous people,
像詹姆斯·帕特森啊  史蒂芬·金之类的
like James Patterson and Stephen King.
谁
Who?
拜托  你真觉得卡塞尔会从那些人里挑伴郎
Come on, man -- you really think castle wants one of those guys
来见证他婚礼的神圣时刻吗
standing beside him when he ties the knot?
嗯  有道理
You know, maybe you're right.
过去这么些年  卡塞尔几乎
Castle's spent practically every day in the precinct
每天都在局里
for the past few years.
他没道理不选我们做他的伴郎的
Why wouldn't he ask one of us to be his best man?
你肯定想说他没道理不选你当伴郎
Why wouldn't he pick me to be his best man, is what you mean.
哈维  很明显该选我嘛
Oh, Javi. I'm the obvious choice.
这你还不明白  我也没法解释
If you can't see it, I can't explain it to you.
你们是
Yes?
纽约警察
NYPD.
我住在洛杉矶的时候经常和罗根一起玩
Me and Logan hung out when I lived in L.A.
我很喜欢他
I really liked him.
霍莉  那他是和你住一起吗
Was he staying with you, Holly?
这是你公寓的钥匙吗
Is this a key to your apartment?
不是
No.
我不知道他待在哪
I-I don't know where he was crashing.
那他来看你了吗
Well, did he stop by?
他口袋里有你的住址
'cause your address was in his pocket.
对  他来过  但很奇怪
Yeah, he did, but it was weird.
上星期罗根突然给我打电话
Logan called last week out of the blue.
他要坐飞机来  还问我
He was flying into town, and he asked
能不能把一个小盒子寄过来
if he can have a small box shipped here.
盒子要是不大的话
Well, if it was small,
他为什么不自己带上飞机呢
why didn't he just take it with him on the plane?
他说不想和运输安全局打交道
He didn't want to deal with TSA
运输安全局总给他添麻烦
because he said they always gave him a hard time.
盒子里有什么
What was in the box?
他的滑板工具什么的
Um, his...skateboard tools and stuff.
至少他是这么告诉我的
At least, that's what he said.
但你不相信他吧
But you didn't believe him.
就是他来拿盒子的时候表现得很奇怪
It's just, when he came to get it, he acted kind of strange.
他看到盒子上的胶带松了点
He noticed some tape had come loose on the box,
就非常紧张
And...he freaked out.
让我发誓我没打开盒子
He made me swear I hadn't opened it.
霍莉  你知道盒子里有什么吗
Holly, do you have any idea what was in that box?
不知道
I don't know.
我真不知道
I-I really don't.
你知道他为什么来这儿吗
Do you know why he flew into town in the first place?
为了比赛
For the games.
什么比赛
What games?
罗根是个职业滑板手
Logan was a pro skateboarder.
他是来参加纽约街头体育节的
He was here for the New York Street Sports Festival,
就在切尔西码头
down by Chelsea Piers.
那个街头体育节昨天开始了
Okay, so, the street sports festival kicked off yesterday.
罗根·摩尔参加了
Logan Moore was entered
街头滑板赛
into the street-style skateboarding event
而且有望夺冠
and favored to win.
他的人气还在上涨中
His star was on the rise.
而且加上他卑微的出身就更令人佩服了
It's all the more impressive given his humble origins.
简历上写着罗根出生于布朗克斯区
Logan's bio says he was born in the Bronx.
在他母亲入狱后他一直在寄养家庭中辗转
He bounced around foster care after his mother went to prison.
之后他去了加利福尼亚  成了滑板手
Then he ran off to California, made his mark as a skater,
一心一意干了这行
and never looked back.
接着被一个带枪摩托车手干掉了
And then he was killed by a gun-wielding biker.
这点虽然简历上没写  但是这事不简单
Not in the bio, but, obviously, there's more to the story.
鉴证科辨认出了案发现场的车辙
Hey. So, CSU I.D.ed those tracks at the scene.
是米其林S12系列越野轮胎
They were made by michelin S12s, a type of off-road tire.
为什么要在街上骑越野车
Why would someone ride an off-road bike on the streets?
完全是浪费越野胎啊
That would just wear the tires down to nothing.
除非那是凶手唯一能用的轮胎
Unless it's the only type of bike the killer had access to.
体育节的一个重要项目就是摩托车越野赛
One of the main events at the games is motocross,
他们用的正是这种轮胎
and those are the tires they use.
鉴证科在查是否有符合现场车辙的车
CSU's checking to see if any of those are a match to the tarck.
好的
Okay, good.
那么  凶手可能是比赛相关人员
So, our killer could be connected to the games.
我打赌是曼尼·卡斯特罗
Yep. And I'm laying money it was Manny Castro.
曼尼·卡斯特罗是谁
And who is Manny Castro?
一个和罗根有嫌隙的职业滑板手
A top pro who had beef with Logan.
六个月前  罗根在洛杉矶赢了他
Six months ago, Logan showed him up at an event in Los Angeles,
之后又赢过他两次
then beat him two more times after that.
他俩的关系已经剑拔弩张了
Tension got super-high between the two of them.
一个无法接受失败的擂主
Oh. A reigning champion unable to cope with defeat,
怎么有点耳熟呢
that sounds familiar.
结果昨天  他俩动手了
Yeah, but then yesterday, things got physical.
一个粉丝在YouTube上发的
A fan posted this on YouTube.
我跟你说话呢  罗根
Hey! I'm talking to you, Logan!
你敢不理我
You think you can just walk away from me?!
放开我
Get off me, man!
你的滑板生涯结束了  你完了
Your skating days are done! You're done!
听到了吗  罗根
You hear me, Logan?!
-曼尼·卡斯特罗在哪  -就在赛场
- Where's Manny Castro now? - At the venue.
街头比赛刚完  他赢了
The street-style event just ended, and Manny won.
这个甩尾真漂亮
Whoa! Nice tail whip!
你还知道专业术语啊
Oh. So you know the lingo?
你还有什么我不知道的体育史吗
Any extreme sports in your history I've yet to hear about?
我觉得追凶就挺极限了
Well, I mean, I think catching killers is pretty extreme.
嫁给你也是
And then there's marrying you.
我的确超出常人
Ah, yes. I admit I am extreme.
超出常人的帅气
Extremely handsome.
没错  而且还很别扭
Yep -- with a high degree of difficulty.
那就是曼尼
There's Manny.
给你一个大爱心
Big heart for you.
-谢谢  -曼尼·卡斯特罗
- Thanks. - Manny Castro?
是我
Yeah, that's me.
纽约警察  想和你谈谈罗根·摩尔
NYPD. We need to talk to you about Logan Moore.
废物一个  有什么好谈的
Guy's a loser. What's there to talk about?
谈谈他被杀的事吧
How about his murder?
罗根没来比赛
When Logan didn't show up for the event,
我也不知道他怎么了
I-I didn't know what to think,
但我可没杀他
but I sure as hell didn't kill him.
曼尼  你在洛杉矶输给他之后
Manny, you repeatedly swore to do just that
多次发誓说要杀了他
after he beat you in L.A.
还有奥斯汀市和坦帕市的失败
And in Austin. And tampa.
我总是说大话  粉丝们就喜欢这个
I talk a lot of trash. The fans go nuts for it.
那只是表演而已
It's all part of the show.
我们去问过你所在旅馆的前台了
We talked to the front desk at your hotel.
他们说你昨晚10点左右离开后
They say that you left at 10:00 p.M. Last night
今天凌晨5点才回来
and you didn't come back until 5:00 a.M.
我找了个女孩
I hooked up with a girl.
她能证明我昨晚和她在一起
She'll tell you I was with her all night.
我相信她会的
Yeah, I'm sure she will.
但是你昨天威胁罗根的视频
But that video of you threatening Logan yesterday,
将是更难以辩驳的证据
that's gonna be a lot harder to explain away.
不是那样的
No. That's not what it looks like.
是吗  看起来也什么歧义啊
Really? 'cause it looks like it is what it looks like.
就在视频的事发生之前
Listen, right before that video was taken,
我抓到罗根在翻摩托车比赛办公室
I caught Logan ransacking the festival mobile office, all right?
什么叫翻  捣乱吗
Ransacking as in trashing?
更像是在找东西
It was more like he was looking for something.
-找什么  -我不知道
- Like what? - I don't know.
他也不愿说  所以我才找他的麻烦的
And he wouldn't explain himself, so I got up in his face.
那才是视频里的发生事
That's what was on the videotape.
你告发他了吗
You report it?
我本来要告诉汤姆·弗顿的
I was gonna tell Tom Fulton,
就是体育节的执行总裁
the festival C.E.O.,
但是他求我不要  所以我就没说
But he begged me not to, so I kept my mouth shut.
你为什么要这么做
And why would you do that for him?
罗根求我保密24小时
Logan asked me for 24 hours.
他发誓说这事关乎生死
He swore it was a matter of life and death.
看来还真是这样
I guess he was right.
我能帮你什么吗
Can I help you?
我是贝克特探长
Yeah. I'm detective Beckett.
这是我的同事  卡塞尔先生
This is my associate, Mr. Castle.
我们想见汤米·弗顿
Uh, we're looking for Tommy Fulton.
我就是
That's me.
新闻报道了罗根·摩尔被杀的事
News just broke Logan Moore was killed.
我感到很难过
I'm sick about it.
你是来调查谋杀案还是闯入案的
You -- you here about that or the break-in.
都要调查
Both, actually.
你最后一次见罗根是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Logan?
两天前  他来这里训练时
Two days ago. He was here doing some practice runs.
他有没有和这里的谁发生过争执
Did he have any issues with anyone here
或者在赛程中和谁有过冲突
or trouble with anyone on the circuit?
大家都想赢
Oh, the guys play to win,
不过输赢只是赛场上的事
but it stays out in the park, you know?
有什么东西被偷吗
So, what was taken from here?
目前为止  我能确定丢失了的
Uh, so far, the only thing I know missing for sure
就是我的枪
I-is my gun.
我抽屉有把45毫米手枪  登记在册的
I kept a .45 in my desk -- legally registered.
罗根知道你有枪吗
Did Logan know about the gun?
你觉得进来的是罗根吗
What -- you think Logan broke in here?
我猜这不像他的为人
I'm assuming that would have been out of character?
当然不像  他可是下一个托尼·霍克[滑板高手]
Hell yes. He was on his way to becoming the next Tony Hawk.
罗根有什么需要枪的理由吗
Is there any reason that Logan would have needed a gun?
我了解罗根  他的童年很艰辛
I know Logan. He had a tough go of things growing up.
这也不是第一次这样的孩子
It wouldn't be the first time a kid like that
和坏人搅在一起了
fell in with a bad crowd.
什么坏人
What bad crowd?
罗根刚来登记时
When Logan first came here to register,
我记得他接到了一个很奇怪的电话
I remember he gets this weird phone call.
他接了电话说道  "那么多年了
He answers and he says, "You got some nerve
你居然还敢打电话让我干这事
"asking me to do this after all these years.
离我远点  别再给我来电话了"
"Stay the hell out of my life. Don't ever call me again."
然后他就把电话挂了
Then he hung up.
你知道他在和谁通话吗
Any idea who he was talking to?
不知道
No.
但当时他很惊慌失措
But he was pretty shook up.
如果他拿了我的枪然后被杀害
If he took my gun and someone killed him,
也许和这个有关联
maybe there's a connection.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
曼尼·卡斯特罗的不在场证明核实了
Hey. So, Manny Castro's alibi checks.
而且我问过罗根的对手
And I talked to Logan's competition.
没有人记得
None of them remember anything
他和坏人混在一起
about him hanging out with a bad crowd.
如果坏人指的是一个邪恶的阴谋组织
What if that bad crowd refers to an evil cabal
雇佣极限运动员与死神搏斗
that pays extreme athletes to duel to the death,
只为让堕落的百万富翁牟利
all for the benefit of depraved millionaires?
你是说像电影《疯狂轮滑》那样吗
You mean like the movie "Rollerball"?
这就解释了"摩托车对阵滑板"谋杀案
It would explain the "motorcycle VS. skateboard" murder.
或者这和阿尔巴尼亚黑帮有关
Or maybe it has something to do with the Albanian mob.
-什么  -嗯
- What?! - Yeah.
根据他的电话记录
According to his phone records,
罗根接到多通布朗克斯
Logan received a dozen calls
一个社交俱乐部打来的电话
from a social club in the Bronx.
那是与组织犯罪有关的阿尔巴尼亚人开的
The place is run by Albanians linked to organized crime.
阿尔巴尼亚黑帮是不是以疯狂暴力而臭名远昭
Isn't the Albanian mob infamous for being crazy-violent?
看看能不能查出是谁从那个俱乐部打电话给他
See if you can find out who was calling him from that club.
马上去查
I'm on it.
卡塞尔  给你样东西
Oh. Castle, I-I got something for you.
你喜欢的那只笔
It's that pen you liked.
这可是传家宝
It's an heirloom.
-今天是什么日子  -没什么日子
- What's the occasion? - There's no occasion.
因为我们是哥们
It's just 'cause we're -- 'cause we're bros.
铁哥们
Best bros.
真是太正点了
This is fantastic.
才没有  多幼稚啊
No, it's not. It's juvenile.
那个
So...
罗根的财务状况告诉了我们他住哪
Logan's financials got us a line on where he was staying.
整个礼拜  他都从GrubHub叫外卖
All week, he'd been ordering from GrubHub.
你是说那家餐饮服务
You mean the food service?
是的  他们送外卖到苏豪区的一个阁楼
Yeah, they were delivering meals to a loft in SoHo.
是谁的阁楼
Whose loft was it?
一个衣食无忧的孩子  喜欢和运动员开派对
Some trust-fund kid -- likes to party with the athletes.
名字叫罗斯·迪·科宁
Guy named Ross De Koning.
漂亮  兄弟
Nice, brother.
也不是很难啦
It's not really all that hard.
你能做得更好吗
Oh, yeah. Like you could do better?
你是罗斯·迪·科宁
Um...hi. Ross De Koning?
纽约警察局
Uh, NYPD.
我得说  这个派对随时欢迎你
I just got to say, you can come party here anytime.
明天你可以
In fact, swing by tomorrow
来参加我非常特别的21岁生日聚会
for my very special 21st birthday bash.
听起来挺诱人的
Look, as tempting as that sounds.
我们其实是想问你几个问题
Um, we actually just need to ask you a few questions
关于罗根·摩尔的
about Logan Moore.
是的  我对发生的一切感到很沮丧
Oh, yeah. I was so bummed by what happened.
我知道他一直住在这儿
I understand that he had been staying here.
是的  我们曾一起玩过滑板
Oh, yeah. I mean, we used to skate together.
所以当他说想在这住  我立马就答应了
So when he asked to crash, I was like, "Absolutely."
你看见他昨晚什么时候离开了吗
And did you see him when he left last night?
没有  我没有注意到
No. I don't keep tabs.
罗根搬去加州之前
Before he moved to California,
和阿尔巴尼亚黑帮有没有什么联系
did Logan have any connections to the Albanian mob?
天啊
Oh, man.
你认为那个阿尔巴尼亚人杀了他
You think the Albanian killed him?
什么阿尔巴尼亚人
What Albanian?
我从没想过这点
That never even entered my mind.
罗斯  什么阿尔巴尼亚人
Ross, what Albanian?
那是五六年前
So, maybe five, six years ago,
罗根的妈妈和一个叫恩韦尔的男人约过会
Logan's mom dated this dude -- Enver.
他吸毒还干各种坏事
He was into drugs and all kinds of bad stuff.
罗根和恩韦尔之间有过什么纠葛吗
Was there ever any trouble between Logan and Enver?
很大的纠葛
Major trouble.
罗根把恩韦尔送进了监狱
Logan helped send Enver to prison,
恩韦尔发誓说他要报复
and Enver swore he'd get even
不达目的决不罢休
if it was the last thing he'd do.
恩韦尔·科塔
Enver Kotta --
因持械抢劫  袭击和非法占有被定罪
Convictions for armed robbery, assault, and possession.
根据案件资料
According to the case file,
罗根的妈妈要么是傻到
Logan's mom either had the bad sense
让恩韦尔把可卡因藏在她公寓里
to let Enver stash his cocaine at her apartment
要么就是她参与了贩毒活动
or she was in on the whole drug operation.
总之  罗根看不下去了就报警了
Bottom line is, Logan got sick of it and called the cops.
罗根的妈妈被判入狱七年
Logan's mom ended up getting seven years,
然而恩韦尔只判了五年
while Enver did five.
我猜猜  恩韦尔做了个交易  把她坑了
Let me guess. Enver cut a deal, threw her under the bus?
是的  另外
Yep. And guess what else.
恩韦尔上个月刚刚假释出狱
Enver just got out on parole last month.
当他得知罗根来这儿了
So when he realized Logan was in town,
就去找他算账了
he went looking for payback.
看来
Hey, so, it looks like
罗根肯定和这家伙有联系
Logan definitely had contact with this guy.
原来恩韦尔是那个
Turns out that Enver was a regular
打来电话的俱乐部的常客
at that social club where the calls came from.
好的  把他带来问话
Okay. Let's pick him up.
不管那孩子发生了什么事  都和我无关
Whatever happened to that kid, I had nothing to do with it.
罗根害你坐了五年牢
You served five years because of Logan.
你要找他复仇已经不是什么秘密了
It was no secret that you wanted him to pay.
你就是为这个打给他吗
Is that why you called him?
告诉他你要怎么对付他
To let him know what you were gonna do to him?
我没有杀罗根
I didn't kill Logan.
那昨晚三点到四点之间你在哪
Then where were you last night between 3:00 and 4:00 A.M.?
我来帮你回答吧  恩韦尔
Let me help you out, Enver.
你的信用卡显示你1点15分在一家餐馆里
Your credit card puts you at a diner at 1:15 A.M.,
那里有个目击证人看到你和罗根一起
where a witness saw you with Logan.
那个目击证人说罗根离开后
That same witness said that when Logan left,
你跟上了他
you followed him out.
几个小时后  罗根被杀了
A few hours later, Logan was dead.
是的  昨晚我见过他
Okay. I met with him last night.
但我没想要报复
But I didn't want revenge.
那你想干什么
Then what did you want?
监狱改变了我
Prison changed me.
我皈依了上帝
I found the lord.
为了完成自我改变
Working my program means making amends
我得为之前的错误赎罪
for the things that I've done wrong.
你以为我们会相信
Do you expect us to believe
你和罗根见面是为了道歉
that you met up with Logan to apologize?
他也不相信我
He didn't believe me, either.
所以我不断地打电话给他
So I kept calling him and calling him.
昨天他回我电话了  说如果我给他三千
He phoned back yesterday, said he'd meet me --
他就肯见我
if I gave him $3,000.
他为什么要三千块
Why would he want 3 grand?
他只说他需要这笔钱
He just said he needed it.
如果这就是和他面对面的代价
And if that was the price to sit down with him, Well...
那我愿意付这笔钱
I was willing to pay it.
所以我凑齐了现金
So I scraped up the cash.
他肯定到现在还怕我
He must have still been afraid of me.
他带了一支枪去了餐馆
He showed up at the diner with a piece.
我把钱给他
I gave him the money,
告诉他我很抱歉将他的生活弄得一团糟
said how sorry I was for messing up his life,
告诉他我愿为他妈做有利证明
told him I'd even testify on his mama's behalf,
想让她早点放出来
try to get her released early.
那你们俩之后做什么了
And what did the two of you do afterwards?
他只说他要趁来得及去处理点事
He just said he had to take care of something before it was too late.
然后他就离开了
Then he took off.
而我  就回家了
And I...went home.
卡塞尔
Castle.
我有东西要给你
I, uh, have something for you.
-给我  -是的
- For me? - Yeah.
肉馅土豆馅饼的配方
Recipe for shepherd's pie.
就是珍妮那天晚上做的那种吗
Is this the one Jenny made that night?
太好吃了
That was outstanding.
-你还记得你问她是怎么做的吗  -是的
- You remember you asked how she made it? - Yeah.
这是她祖母家的祖传秘方
Well, this is her grandma's secret family recipe --
而我已经把你当成自家人了
Because I think of you as family.
谢谢你  莱恩
Thank you, Ryan.
我太感动了
I'm touched.
我永远都会照应你  卡塞尔  别忘了
Always looking out for you, Castle. Remember that.
罗根住的那个地方的看门人罗斯说
So, the doorman at Ross' place, where Logan was staying,
罗根昨天晚上一点半回到了住处
says that Logan came back to the building last night at 1:30 A.M.
这说明他在吃完饭后回了家
Which means he returned to the building after the diner,
这就证实了恩韦尔的话
and that supports Enver's story.
是的  但是罗根那时还没忙完
Yeah, but Logan wasn't done for the night.
他是回去拿东西的
He was picking something up.
看门人说他只进去了一小会儿
Doorman says that he went inside for a sec,
然后就拿着个黑色行李包出来了
came back out carrying a black duffel bag.
行李包
A duffel bag?
看门人知道里面是什么吗
Could the doorman tell what was inside?
不知道  但是他看出那包很重
No, but he said it was heavy,
所以他想帮罗根叫辆出租车
so he offered to hail a cab.
罗根拒绝了  然后跳上滑板就走了
Logan refused and jumped on his skateboard and rolled away.
犯罪现场没有什么行李包
There was no duffel bag at the scene.
可能凶手拿走了
Maybe the killer took it.
派警员去罗斯住处和犯罪现场之间的区域搜寻
Canvass the area between Ross' building and our crime scene.
如果我们能知道罗根要把那包带去哪
If we can figure out where Logan was taking that bag,
应该就能找到凶手了
that should lead us to our killer.
我们马上去查
We'll get into it.
可以回家了吗
You ready to go home?
是的  我也真有点累了
Yeah. Yeah, I am. I'm actually kind of tired.
我希望你不是很累  还能...
I hope not too tired to...you know.
D拼Dyad[二分体]
And "D" for "Dyad,"
是指两个人谈话  就像我们现在这样
which means two people talking, as we are now.
实际上  大部分时间都是你在说
Well, actually, it's been mostly you talking.
或者更准确地说  是在吹牛
Well, bragging, to be specific.
好了  单词得9分
Okay, word score's a 9,
而且有双倍得分  就是18分
plus the double word score brings it to 18,
加上A和Y的5分
plus the 5 from the "A" "Y",
总共是23分
that's a total of 23,
所以我的总分是312分
bringing my score to 312,
而你只有区区的175分
versus your paltry 175.
卡塞尔  难道没有比获胜更重要的事了吗
Castle, aren't there more important things than winning?
这句话是用来安慰输了的人的
That's a notion created to comfort those who lose.
我是在想我们可以做一些
Well, I was thinking that we could be doing
更有趣的事
something more interesting with our time.
这样的话
Well, in that case,
那我们就赶紧结束这场比赛吧
let's hurry up and finish this game.
好吧  那我认输怎么样
Okay. How about I concede?
剥夺我胜利的快感吗
And steal my moment of triumph?
不行  不是真正获胜就不算数
No. It doesn't count if it's not official.
现在该你下了  感受一下失败的痛苦吧
Now, just take your turn and feel the bitter sting of defeat.
好吧
Fine.
Quixotic[不切实际的]
"Quixotic"?
是的
Yeah.
这个词含有字母Q和C  可以三倍得分
So, that's a triple word score with the "Q" And the "C,"
以及含有字母X  可以双倍得分
plus a double letter score with the "X"
还有对我用完所有字母的50分额外奖励
and another 50-point bonus for using all of my letters.
一共多少分
How many points is that?
314分
314.
抱歉  卡塞尔
I'm sorry, Castle.
我想我要一个人待会儿
I think I need to be alone.
好的  有新消息通知我  谢了  比尔
All right. Keep me posted. All right. Thanks, Bill.
伙计  我一直在想
Hey, man. I've been thinking.
卡塞尔对我们两个都很喜欢
You know, Castle likes us both too much
所以很难选出谁当伴郎
to have to make the pick for best man.
我们应该替他来决定
So we should make the decision for him.
这是他的婚礼啊
Um... it's his wedding.
我们怎么能替他做决定
How do you propose we decide for him?
我们其中一个人要退出
One of us is gonna have to drop out.
"其中一个人"就是指"你"
And by "One of us," I mean "You."
我
Me?
为什么是我
Why should it be me?
因为
Because.
你觉得理查德·卡塞尔
You think Richard Castle
会想让你来策划他的单身汉舞会吗  傻兄弟
wants you planning his bachelor party? Come on, bro.
埃斯波西托
Oh, Esposito.
做伴郎可不仅仅是要
See, being a best man is a lot more
策划单身汉舞会
than just preparing the bachelor party.
我是有家室的人
I'm a family man.
我代表了更高的道德水准
I represent a high moral standing.
得了吧
Oh, please.
而且我的摄影技术比你高
And I photograph better than you.
什么
What?
我告诉你吧  你要完了
Let me tell you something -- you're going down.
你给我记好了  我可是给你台阶下了
And just remember that I gave you an opportunity to bow out gracefully.
听见了吗
You hear me?
是的
Okay.
卡塞尔  哥们  怎么样了
Castle. Hey, buddy. How's it going?
别问
Don't ask.
作为你最好的朋友  我不得不问
Well, as your close friend, now I have to ask.
她是不是又赢了拼字游戏
did she beat you at scrabble again?
拜托  我们能不能谈谈案子
Can we just talk about the case, please?
当然
Sure. You bet.
去调查罗根
So, the canvass to narrow down
把行李包带去了哪的警员一无所获
where Logan went with his duffel last night came up empty.
但是  还记得我们在他身上找到的钥匙吗
But, uh, you remember the key that we found on him?
鉴证组发现它属于一家24小时营业的健身房
Well, CSU, they traced it back to a 24-hour gym,
而且罗根在他遇害当晚
and it turns out that Logan was there
3点至4点就在那里
3:00 and 4:00 A.M. the night he was murdered.
这么说他临死前去的最后一个地方是健身房
So the last place he went before he was killed was a gym.
而且他待的时间不长
And he didn't stay long.
他的会员卡刷进
His membership card was swiped in
和刷出只相差了两分钟
and then swiped right back out two minutes later.
放下行李包的时间是足够了
Just long enough to drop off a duffel bag.
是的  我对罗根印象很深
Yeah, I totally remember Logan.
他每天去石墙那边
He was in here every day on the rock wall,
练习攀岩
Practicing his climbing.
这是他的更衣柜
This is his locker.
两天前的晚上你看到他来过吗
Did you see him come in two nights ago?
那晚我不工作  但是我们有监控录像
I wasn't on duty, but we have security video.
我想我能给你们一份
I'm sure I can get you a copy.
卡塞尔  在这里
Castle, it's here.
看看
Look at this.
攀岩装备
Climbing gear?
是的
Yeah.
和一把点45口径手枪
And a .45.
一定是罗根从汤米·弗顿那偷的那把
This must be the one that Logan stole from Tommy Fulton.
可他那晚为什么需要手枪和攀岩绳呢
But why would he need a gun and climbing ropes that night?
螺丝刀  扳手
Screwdrivers, wrenches.
那个应该是玻璃刀
And that would be a glass cutter.
还有开锁工具
And tension tools...
撬锁用的
For picking locks.
罗根·摩尔不是简单的滑板冠军
So, Logan Moore wasn't just a champion skateboarder.
他是个小偷
He was a thief.
罗根·摩尔的家庭充满不幸
Logan Moore, child of a broken home
他在滑板中找到了慰藉和乐趣所在
who found solace and salvation on a skateboard.
但他有没有利用极限运动好手的身体条件
But did he use his skills as an extreme athlete
成为了一名神偷呢
to become a master thief?
这位不羁的滑板手是否真的成了法外之徒
Did our outlaw skater become an actual outlaw?
若他是个小偷  那他到底偷了什么
If he was a thief, then what did he steal?
在他身上和储物柜里
We didn't find anything of value
没有发现任何贵重物品
in his locker or on his body.
也许是被凶手拿走了
Well, maybe the killer took it.
也许这是他被害的原因
Maybe that's why he targeted Logan.
鉴证组正在处理那个健身房包
So, while CSU was processing that gym bag,
他们找到一张他死亡那天的收据
they found this receipt inside from the day he died.
电子商品店的收据
From an electronics store?
是的  店在中城区
Yeah, in midtown.
店主说他记得罗根
The owner there said he remembered Logan
因为他想买一个超8摄像机
because he asked for a Hi8 camcorder.
超8  这种格式已经过时了
Hi8? That's an outdated format.
是的  他卖出的那台已有10年历史了
Sure is. The one he sold him was 10 years old.
那他为什么要买一台10年前的摄像机呢
So, why would he buy a 10-year-old camcorder?
也许他想拍下他的犯罪过程
Maybe he wanted to film his crime?
为什么不用手机或者GoPro呢
Why not use a cellphone or a GoPro?
伙计们  过来看看这个
Hey, guys. Come check this out.
多谢
Thanks.
我们查看了健身房的监控记录
So, we ran through security footage of the gym
想看看罗根寄存包的时候
to see if anybody was with Logan
是否有人和他一起  或者被跟踪
when he dropped off the bag or if anyone followed him out.
这是我们的发现
Here's what we found.
这些监控记录的截图
These photograbs correspond to the exact time
是在罗根刷门卡时截取的
Logan's card was swiped.
等等  那不是罗根
Wait a minute. That's not Logan.
不是  不过我们之前见过他
No, but we've seen him before.
是的  在罗斯·迪·科宁阁楼派对上
Yeah, at Ross De Koning's penthouse party.
他连帽衫下面穿着街头运动的T恤
And he's wearing a street sports tee underneath his hoodie,
于是我们查了他们的网站
so we checked out their website.
他的名字是卡特·维斯兰德
His name is Carter Wexland.
他也是参赛选手之一
He's one of the competitors,
罗根肯定也认识他
so Logan would have known him.
我查了他的档案
Pulled his file.
他有非法闯入和重偷窃罪的犯罪记录
He has a record for B&Es and grand theft.
而且
And...
他还是一名越野摩托车手
He's also a motocross rider.
正如此案的凶手
Just like our killer.
我去了健身房  那又怎样
So, I went to the gym. So what?
在凌晨3点40分去的
At 03:40 A.M.
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep.
没什么大不了的
What's the big deal?
问题大着呢  卡特·维斯兰德先生
The big deal, Mr. Wexland,
你用罗根·摩尔的健身卡的时候
is that you used Logan Moore's I.D. Card
正是他在那附近被人杀害的时候
when he had just been killed nearby.
不难想象你是从哪里弄到的健身卡
Ain't hard to figure out where you got it.
他前一天借给我的  这样我才能健身
Yeah. He loaned it to me the day before so I could work out.
你健身的时间真短
That was a quick workout,
你进去出来一共就花了两分钟
considering you were there for only two minutes.
你进去是为了寄放那个旅行包
You went there to drop off this duffel bag.
罗根在那晚早些时候也带着同样的包
And since Logan was carrying this exact bag
我们相信你们俩一定见过面
earlier that night, we know the two of you crossed paths.
我真希望你能看到你自己的表情
I wish you could see your face right now.
就像霓虹灯一样闪烁着"是我干的"
It's like this neon sign flashing "I did it!"
情况如何
How's it going?
他快顶不住压力了
They got him on the run.
我想你肯定要点提神饮料
I, uh, thought you could use a little pick-me-up.
多谢
Thanks. Uh-huh.
朋友就应该互相照顾不是吗
That's what friends are for, right?
是的
Right. Mm-hmm.
婚礼计划得怎么样了
Oh, hey, uh, how are the wedding plans going?
都还顺利吗
Everything good?
顺利  都很好
Yeah. Yeah, great.
不错
Great.
如果有什么事情我能帮忙的话
Well, if there's anything I-I can do to help --
随便什么脏活累活
You know, literally, symbolically --
只管说
Just...let me know.
好的
I will.
到底发生了什么  伙计
So, what happened, bro?
你们俩合伙干了一票
The two of you did a job together?
结果意见不合吵起来了
And you had a falling-out,
于是你决定你要独吞战果
then you decided you didn't want to share the score?
伙计  听我说  我没有杀人
Dude, I'm telling you -- I didn't kill anyone.
拜托  卡特  你有他的包和健身卡
Come on, Carter. You had his bag and his I.D. on you.
你距他被杀的地方就几个街区远
You were blocks away from where he was killed,
你也是个越野摩托车手
And you ride a motocross bike.
再加上你的犯罪记录
With your criminal record,
检察官判你有罪想都不用想
this is gonna be a slam dunk for the D.A.
不  不  听我说
No, no. I'm telling you.
那晚我最后一次见到罗根时  他还活着
The last time I saw Logan that night, he was still alive.
你终于承认你见过他了
So you admit to having seen him.
是的
Yes.
好的
Okay.
他听说了我的过去于是雇我帮他做事
He heard about my past and hired me for a job.
做什么
Okay. So, what was the job.
非法闯入
A B&E.
他承诺若我能解除报警系统就给我三千块
He told me he'd give me 3 grand to bypass an alarm system
还让我在房顶帮他栓好绳索
and belay him from a rooftop
这样他就能潜入一个位于15楼的办公室
so that he could get into a 15th-floor office.
什么办公室
What office?
我不知道  我那会儿在房顶
I don't know. I was on the roof.
他切开窗户玻璃之后进去了
He cut in through the window, went in,
然后把装备装在包里送了上来
and then sent up the gear with the bag.
那是我最后一次见到他
That was the last I saw him.
计划是我要带着那些装备离开现场
The plan was for me to disappear with the gear
然后把包存放在健身房
and then stash the bag at the gym.
他有带一个摄像机吗
Did he have a camcorder with him?
有
Yeah.
之前包里有一个
I-I mean, there was one in the bag.
不过他把送上来之后就不在了
But it wasn't there when he sent it back.
他跟你说他在找什么了吗
Did he tell you what he was after?
没有
No.
不过当我知道要这么麻烦时
But when I saw all the trouble that we were going to,
我跟罗根说我要提成
I told Logan I wanted a cut,
而不仅仅是三千块
not just the 3 grand.
他听了很生气
He got really pissed
说他可不是什么罪犯
and said he wasn't some criminal
这也不是有关钱的事
and this wasn't about money.
是替一个死去的朋友讨回公道
It was about making things right for a friend who died.
他当时很激动
He was really intense.
我就相信了他
I believed him.
罗根跟你说是他哪个朋友了吗
Did Logan tell you who this friend was?
不  他没说
No. He didn't.
提前把工具邮过来  雇佣帮手
Shipping his tools ahead, hiring an accomplice --
同时利用一个滑板活动做掩护
All the while using a skateboarding event as a cover.
在我看来罗根回到纽约的真正原因
Seems to me the real reason Logan came back to New York
就是来行窃
was to commit this burglary.
但他到底要偷什么
Yeah, but what was he stealing,
这和他这位去世的朋友又有什么联系
and how is it related to this dead friend?
那我再去问问认识罗根的人
Well, I'll circle back around to the people who knew Logan,
看他们对闯入知不知情  认不认识这个死去的朋友
see if anybody knows of any break-ins or a dead friend.
对了  卡塞尔
Oh, and, Castle,
你想不想和我一起去趟滑板公园
do you want to come with me down to the skate park?
我们可以顺便
I thought maybe we could stop by
去吃你喜欢的培根布朗尼
and get some of those bacon brownies that you love.
有培根我当然去
You had me at bacon.
你最好先别急着答应
Uh, well, you might want to hold off on that offer.
卡特和罗根闯入的那栋大楼
That building that Carter and Logan broke into
离罗根被害地点只有几个街区
was only a few blocks from where Logan was killed.
但我查过出警记录
Yet I checked the police blotter.
当晚那附近没有接到任何闯入的报警
There were no reported break-ins there that evening.
根据卡特的描述
But based on Carter's description,
我查到了罗根破窗而入的15楼的
I was able to identify which 15th-floor window
所有者是谁了
that Logan entered through.
该层是一家属于布伦特·扎列特茨基的律师事务所
It belongs to a law office for a Brett Zaretsky, esquire.
罗根闯入律师事务所做什么
What was Logan doing breaking into a law office?
你们最好去查一查
You guys should probably go find out.
好  来吧卡塞尔  我们走
Yeah. Come on, Castle. Let's go.
改天再吃
Rain check?
好呀
Yeah.
你没觉得埃斯波西托和莱恩最近有点古怪吗
Have you noticed anything odd about Esposito and Ryan lately?
比如
Like what?
他们对我特别好  好得让人发毛
They're being nice to me -- weird nice.
他俩大概是想抚慰一下你那
Well, they probably just feel sorry for you
被我昨晚打得满地找牙的脆弱心灵吧
after the beatdown I gave you in scrabble last night.
你莫要得意  我此仇必报
Gloat all you want. I will have my revenge.
好了  我们去找布伦特·扎列特茨基吧
Okay. Okay. Let's just find Brett Zaretsky right now.
新窗玻璃
New window.
两位有何贵干
Can I help you?
你好  我们是来调查闯入案的
Yeah. Hi. We're here about the break-in.
恐怕二位搞错了
Well, I'm afraid you've been misinformed.
没人破窗闯入你的办公室吗  扎列特茨基先生
A thief didn't break in through your window, mr. Zaretsky?
没有
No.
那为什么要换窗玻璃
Well, why is the glass being replaced?
被小鸟撞坏了
A small mishap with a bird.
小鸟
A bird?
扎列特茨基先生  你认识这个人吗
Mr. Zaretsky, do you recognize this man?
抱歉  我没什么印象
No. I'm sorry. I'm afraid I don't.
你介不介意我们四处查看一下
Would you mind if we took a quick look around?
是啊  我们没准能帮你
Yeah, we might be able to help you
评估一下那小鸟给你造成的损失呢
assess any of the damage this bird might have caused.
我很介意
Yes, I mind.
扎列特茨基先生  前天晚上你或者其他人
Mr. Zaretsky, were you or anyone else here
是否来过这间办公室
two nights ago?
探长  你得先传唤我才能讯问我
Detective, if you want to question me, get a subpoena.
想来事务所查案  先申请搜查令
If you want to come into these offices, get a warrant.
在那之前  我只好请两位离开
Until then, I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
那律师拒绝配合我们
Look, there's only one reason
还拒不上报闯入案的原因只有一个
that lawyer would stonewall us and not report a break-in.
他肯定有所隐瞒
He's covering something up.
可疑的律所  神秘的死亡
Shady law firm, mysterious death,
匡扶正义的有志青年
a young man righting wrongs.
也许罗根·摩尔更像是《永不妥协》女主
Maybe Logan Moore is like Erin Brockovich,
只不过他的武器是滑板
But with a skateboard
而不是  你知道  其他种种
instead of -- you know -- other assets.
你是说头脑
Brains?
没错  就是头脑
Yes, brains. Yeah.
莱恩  你能调查一下布伦特·扎列特茨基的律所吗
Hey, Ryan, can you look into Brett Zaretsky's law firm?
媒体新闻  法庭记录  知名案件什么的
Uh, press releases, court filings, lawsuits.
看能不能查出把他和罗根联系起来的信息
See if there's anything there that connects him to Logan.
这就去
I'm on it.
我去问了汤米  罗斯和霍莉
Hey, I circled back around to Tommy, Ross, and Holly.
就算罗根真的有一位亡友  他们也毫不知情
If any of Logan's friends died, they don't know about it.
总得有人知道的吧
Well, someone must.
你刚说他母亲关在哪里来着
Where did you say that his mom was, again?
泰克尼克监狱
Taconic correctional.
我们去看看她知道些什么
Okay. Let's see if she can shed some...light.
两位  我知道你们想干什么
Guys, I know what you're trying to do,
我知道你们为什么对我这么好
why you're being so nice to me.
贝克特给我提了个醒
Beckett clued me in.
说实话  你们让我更纠结了
And, honestly, it's just making it harder,
所以你们  正常点就行
so just...act normal.
-晕  -晕
- Man. - Man.
我们俩真让他左右为难啊
He really can't decide between us.
这也不能怨他
Yeah, but can you blame him?
可怜娃  两头都是好兄弟
I mean, poor guy. He's in a no-win situation.
话说回来  我可能有办法
But... I may have a solution.
来吧
Come on.
让我先把思路理理清
Okay, let me -- let me get this straight.
你俩想让我决定谁才是卡塞尔的伴郎
You guys want me to decide who should be Castle's best man?
非你莫属啊  你是伴娘
Yeah. It's perfect. You're the maid of honor.
你来选  我们通知卡塞尔  这是多赢局面
So you pick, we let Castle know. Everybody wins.
哈维这不成  她当然会选你
Javi, this is ridiculous. Of course she's gonna pick you.
那是因为我身上有独一无二的
That's because there's no better best-man material
优质伴郎气质
than this man right here.
是吧  心肝
Right, baby?
哈维  就咱俩的历史  你真以为我会选你
Javi, do you really think I'd pick you with our history?
看来大局已定了
Well, I guess that's settled.
这个大局就是  你俩纯属发傻
What's settled is, you two are idiots.
我谁都不会选
I'm not picking either one of you.
知道为什么吗
You want to know why?
因为我不是新郎
Because I'm not the groom.
回见  侦探们
Detectives.
她嘴好毒
She's just mean.
总之我们不能强迫卡塞尔二选一
Well...we can't force Castle to choose between us.
肯定有别的办法
There's got to be another way.
两天前狱警告诉我我儿子死了
Two days ago, the warden told me my son was dead.
我一直在等人来
So I'm just waiting for someone to come along
告诉我那狱警说错了
and tell me that he was wrong --
告诉我他们搞错人了
That there's been some sort of mistake.
节哀顺变
We're sorry for your loss.
我很久之前就失去他了
I lost him a long time ago.
罗根是否跟你提起过他的一位去世的朋友
Did Logan ever talk to you about a friend of his dying?
比如在某些非常情况下
Maybe under unusual circumstances?
怎么了
Why?
因为我们认为这是罗根被害的线索之一
Because we believe that it might be related to Logan's murder.
有个叫杰的
Well, there was Jay.
杰是谁
Who was Jay?
他是我家附近的一个精瘦的小男孩
He was a scrawny little kid from the neighborhood,
比罗根小几岁
a couple years younger than Logan.
他常和附近街区的其他孩子在一起玩
He and some of the other kids in the neighborhood
他们自称为"布朗克斯滑板帮"
used to call themselves "the Bronx Skate Crew."
这些孩子都没什么像样的家庭
None of them... had much of a home life,
所以他们整天都粘在滑板上
so they'd just ride around on their boards all day long
净逛些不该去的地方
and...get into places they shouldn't.
杰是罗根认为为数不多的
But Jay was the one that Logan said
比他滑得还好的人之一
might be even better than he was.
杰是怎么死的
And what happened to Jay?
他死于一场事故
He was killed in some accident --
大概是六年前吧
I don't know -- like six years ago.
警察也没查出个头绪来
Cops never figured out what happened.
罗根当时有没有和你提起过杰的死
Did Logan ever talk about Jay's death at the time?
有任何反常的地方吗
Anything out of the ordinary?
没有  那是第一次他认识的人死了
No. I mean, it was the first time that somebody that he knew died,
所以他...很难过
So he -- he took it hard.
杰·迪克逊  12岁
Jay Dixon, age 12.
死于2008年4月27日
He died April 27th, 2008.
验尸官判定为他杀
Coroner ruled the death a homicide.
但凶手从未找到
It was never solved.
发生什么事了
What happened?
死因是头部受到重创
C.O.D. was blunt-force trauma to the head,
他的尸体是在一处建筑工地找到的
and his body was found at a construction site.
有任何凶手的线索吗
Any leads on who did it?
没有  既没有证人也没有嫌疑人
No. There were no witnesses, no suspects.
总而言之  没什么可调查的线索
All in all, it wasn't much of an investigation.
十二岁的孩子被杀
12-year-old gets killed,
却没有一人去查明真相找出真凶
and no one cares enough to find his murderer.
罗根这么做了
Logan did.
为杰讨回公道
Finding justice for Jay
是他来到纽约的唯一原因
seems to be the very reason he came to New York.
但为什么是现在  六年后
But why now, six years later?
为什么罗根认为他时间不多了
And why did Logan think he was running out of time?
这跟扎列特茨基或是他的律所又有什么关联
And what's the connection to Zaretsky or his law firm?
就算是有关联  我也还没找出来
If there is one, I haven't found it.
他的名字不在这份文件里  也没有对业主
He's not named in this file, and there's no wrongful-death
提出任何过失致死或是任何其他类型的诉讼
or other litigation against the property owners.
联系杰的父母
Okay, get ahold of Jay's parents.
看他们最近有没有跟罗根联系过
Let's see if they've been in contact with Logan recently.
快来看看
Hey, guys. Check it out.
搜索队刚刚在罗根被杀的那条小道尽头
Search team just found this camcorder
发现了这个摄像机
down the block from where logan was killed.
一个超八摄像机
A Hi8 camcorder.
没错  鉴证组很快地检查了一遍
Yeah. CSU gave it a quick look.
上面没有指纹  里面也没有录像带
No prints, no cassette tape.
但看看这里
But check it out.
弹孔  罗根被枪杀时一定拿着这个
Bullet hole. So Logan must have had this on him when he was shot.
看来有人想要撬开录像带槽
Looks like someone tried to pry open the cassette slot.
是的  凶手肯定很想要里面的录像带
Yeah, killer must have wanted whatever was inside.
我知道为什么罗根带着摄像机了
I know why Logan bought the camera.
他并不是想要录像
He didn't intend to record something.
他是想要播放一个旧的录像带
He wanted to play an old cassette tape.
你觉得他就是为了偷一盘录像带
You think that's why he broke into the law offices
才闯进律所吗
to get a Hi8 tape?
杰六年前被杀
Jay was killed six years ago.
如果真的有他被杀的证据
If there was evidence of his death,
有可能会被录在这样的录像带上
It's possible it could be on a format like this.
没错  但我们手里没有录像带啊
Yeah, but we still don't have it.
确定吗
Or do we?
看
Look.
录像带一定在凶手扯出来时被撕断了
The tape must have torn when the killer ripped it out.
而且...
And...
瞧瞧吧
Voil?
我把那个录像带的片段数字化了
So, I was able to digitize that tape fragment
并成功修复了六秒钟图像
and recover about six seconds of footage.
看看这个时间标示  2008年4月27日
Look at the time stamp -- April 27th, 2008.
杰·迪克逊就是在这天被杀的
That's the same date Jay Dixon was killed.
我觉得我能再提高下分辨率
I think I can improve the resolution.
这是个建筑工地吗
Is that a construction site?
这有可能是杰·迪克逊被谋杀的录像
This could be footage of Jay Dixon's murder.
开始了
Here we go.
如果你告诉任何人杰被杀的真相
You ever tell anyone what happened to Jay,
你也会死
you'll be dead, too!
这是汤米·弗顿  纽约街头运动的执行总裁
That's Tommy Fulton, C.E.O. of New York Street Sports.
看来六年后  汤米兑现承诺了
Looks like six years later, tommy made good on that promise.
六年前  罗根目击了他的朋友被杀
Six years ago, Logan witnesses his friend's murder,
汤米威胁罗根如果他告诉别人
and then Tommy threatened to kill Logan
杰被杀的真相  他也会被杀
if he ever told what happened to Jay.
几年后
After all these years,
罗根良心过不去
Logan couldn't live with the guilt
回来揭发真相
and came back to expose the truth.
所以问题是
So, the question is,
录像带为什么会在律所里
what was that tape doing in the law office,
而扎列特茨基到底跟这件事有什么关联
and how is Zaretsky connected to all of this?
我觉得我查清这个问题了
I think I figured that one out.
你觉得是谁在处理街头运动节的
Who do you suppose does all the contract work
所有合约
for the Street Sports Festival?
布伦特·扎列特茨基
Brett Zaretsky?
没错
Yeah.
而且扎列特茨基还是汤米·弗顿的私人律师
And Zaretsky also represents Tommy Fulton personally.
我希望你把我叫到这里来
I hope you have a good reason
能说出个好理由  警探
for dragging us down here, detective.
谋杀这个理由...怎么样
How about...murder?
得了吧
C-come on.
如果又是因为罗根的话  我那天
If this is about Logan, I-I was at a club
从午夜到凌晨四点都在一个俱乐部里做宣传
doing promotions from m-midnight to 4:00 a.m.
那你2008年4月27日在哪里
And where were you on April 27th, 2008 --
杰·迪克逊被杀的那一天
when Jay Dixon was killed?
如果你告诉任何人杰被杀的真相
You ever tell anyone what happened to Jay,
你也会死
you'll be dead, too!
当我今早问你杰·迪克逊的时候
When I asked you earlier this morning about Jay Dixon,
你说你从未听说过这个人
you said that you never heard of him.
你撒谎了
And that was a lie.
这录像带与罗根和杰的死无关
That tape proves nothing about Logan or Jay's deaths.
我可以确认你出现在
I can place you at the scene
六年前未破谋杀案的犯罪现场
of a six-year-old unsolved murder.
我还有间接证据证明
I also have circumstantial evidence
你为了掩盖真相杀了罗根灭口
that you killed Logan in order to cover it up.
你觉得陪审团还需要多少证据
Now, how much more do you think a jury is gonna need
把线索联系起来
in order to connect those dots?
我可以解释的
I can explain.
什么都不要解释  汤米
No, don't explain anything, Tommy.
你隐瞒少年被谋杀的证据
You think you can hide behind attorney/client privilege
还想躲在律师客户保密协议这道保护网后吗
if you conceal evidence of a child's murder?
我会取消你的律师资格证
I will have you disbarred,
然后你就要和你的客户一起受审
and then you will stand trial alongside your client.
或许你该打给你的律师了
Maybe you'd like to call your lawyer.
什么都不要说
Don't say another word.
布伦特  还有什么意义吗
Brett, what's the point?
反正整个计划已经搞砸了
I mean, the whole plan's screwed anyway.
别再自掘坟墓了
Stop digging our graves.
我是不会含冤入狱的
I'm not going down for murders that someone else did.
天呐  闭嘴  汤米
For god's sake, shut your mouth, Tommy.
这次我可不会听你的
No. Not this time.
我觉得你应该离开
I think you should leave now.
你不能把我赶出去
Well, you can't kick me out of here.
这个人是我的客户
This man is my client.
你被炒了
You're fired.
你是要自己离开
Either you leave on your own
还是要我找人把你架走
or I will have you forcibly removed.
汤米
Tommy.
到底发生了什么
What happened?
杰六年前是怎么死的
How did Jay die six years ago?
我  杰和罗根当时开始
I started out making skateboard videos
录滑板视频
with Jay and Logan.
那天  我在给他俩录像
That day, I was taping the two of them
而我的朋友D.K.在做翻板
and my friend D.K. doing tre flips.
小杰  他是天生好手
Little Jay -- he was a natural.
但  D.K.做不来
But... D.K. couldn't do it.
他的滑板技术永远都不及杰
He was never that good on a board.
杰
Jay...
嘴比较损
He had a mouth on him.
他当面嘲笑了D.K.
And he was rubbing it in D.K.'s face.
D.K.发怒了
D.K. just snapped.
他抓起杰
He...grabbed Jay... and...
把他往梁子上撞
...he slammed him against this beam...
一遍又一遍
over and over.
等我们把他拉开的时候
By the time we could pull him off...
杰已经断气了
...Jay was gone.
整个过程都被录了下来
And the whole thing was caught on tape.
罗根
Logan...
他打算报案  但我们都害怕极了
He wanted to tell someone, but we were all too scared.
D.K.想要那录像
D.K. wanted that video.
他害怕失去拥有的一切
He had the most to lose.
所以
So...
我们达成了协议
We cut a deal.
什么协议
What kind of a deal?
五百万美金换那盘录像带
$5 million for the tape.
什么孩子会有五百万
What kind of kid has $5 million?
D.K.有
D.K. Does.
相比他将要从家族里继承的财产
With what he's getting from his family,
五百万只是九牛一毛
it was a drop in the bucket.
所以你才一直保存带子
That's why you had to hang on to the tape.
钱来自于信托基金
The money was in a trust fund.
D.K.要等到21周岁才对它享有所有权
D.K. wouldn't have acess to it until his 21st birthday
所以罗根意识到他必须马上行动
And that's why Logan knew he had to act right away.
因为你会把它交给D.K.
You were gonna turn over the tape,
录像带将随真相一起埋葬
and it was gonna get destroyed, along with the truth.
对
Yeah.
干杯  伙伴们  尽情喝
Cheers, guys. Drink up.
祝我生日快乐
Happy birthday to me.
警探们  很高兴见到你们
Hey, detectives! Stoked to see you.
喜欢我新公司的商标吗
Like my new company logo?
嗯  不错  很独特
Yeah, it's -- it's killer.
罗斯·迪·科宁
In fact, Ross de Koning,
现在我们以涉嫌谋杀罗根·摩尔和
you're under arrest for the murder of Logan Moore.
和杰伊·迪克森的罪名逮捕你
And the murder of Jay Dixon.
你在胡说什么
What are you talking about?
汤米·弗顿已向我们坦白一切
Tommy Fulton told us everything.
D.K.  很抱歉毁了你的生日派对
Sorry to ruin your birthday, D.K.
但往好的方面想  你已经21岁了
But look on the bright side -- the good news is, you're 21 now.
这意味着你有了信托基金的掌控权
You have control of your trust fund,
有足够的钱来为自己辩护
so you'll have plenty of money to spend on your defense.
不需要  因为你们没有证据
Well, I won't have to, brah, 'cause you got no proof.
我想我们会找到证据的  在我们检查
I think we will, brah -- after we take a look
你放在车库的越野摩托车后
at that motocross bike in your garage
再与犯罪现场留下的轮胎痕迹做个比对
and match it to the tire treads at the crime scene.
现在他们正在搜查你的阁楼
We have officers searching your loft right now.
你觉得他们找到那把杀死罗根的枪的机会有多大
What are the odds they find the 9mm you used to kill Logan?
还想跑
Where you going? Huh?
有汤米的证词  地检有信心
With Tommy's testimony, the D.A. is confident
以两项谋杀罪将罗斯·迪·科宁定罪
that he's gonna get Ross de Koning convicted for both murders.
至少罗根的愿望实现了
At least Logan succeeded in his quest.
他为朋友伸张了正义
He found justice for his friend.
回想这一切
And to think all this happened
只因为罗斯不甘屈居第二
because Ross couldn't bear being second-best.
你准备好再战一场了吗
So, are you ready for another rematch?
你确定
Really?
你不会剥夺我翻盘的权利吧
You would deny me a chance at redemption?
照此下去  你被夺去的可不止于此了
Well, keep on this path, there's a lot you'll be denied.
卡塞尔  过来聊两句
Hey, Castle. You got a minute?
男人间的谈话
Yeah, we need to have a little man chat.
我还有些报告要整理
There...are some...reports that I have to file.
嗯
Yeah.
我们想了很久
So, we've been doing a lot of thinking.
知道你纠结无比
And, uh, well, we know what you're going through.
你们知道
You do? Yeah.
我们知道那有多难
We know how tough it's been,
所以我们决定别让你难做
so we decided to make it easy for you.
真的吗
You did?
我们谈过了
Yeah. We talked it over.
现在你不必二选一了
And now you don't have to choose.
我们都会是你的伴郎
We'll both be your best man.
双伴郎
Co-best men.
相信我  我们会好好做的
And, believe me, we're gonna do it up right for you.
两全其美
Best of both worlds, buddy.
兄弟们  我受宠若惊
Guys, I'm, uh, I'm flattered and, uh...and honored.
-不客气  -应该的
- You're welcome. - Yeah, you should be.
但我已经作出选择了
But...I already decided.
-你作出了正确选择  -你选的是我对吗
- You made the right choice. - You're talking about me, right?
我想我们会配合得很好的
I think we're gonna have a great time.
因为我们了解对方
'cause it's like, we know each other.
我刚想到个主意
The ideas that I've already
太赞了
come up with are pretty amazing.
我知道最好的餐厅
I know the best restaurant.
你喜欢什么吗  因为我可是那的贵宾
Do you like...'cause I am on the V.I.P. --
兄弟们
Guys.
阿丽克西斯会做我的伴郎
I asked Alexis to be my best man.
除了贝克特
Aside from Beckett,
她是我一生中最重要的人
she's the most important person in my life,
所以我
So I --
你们会做我的男傧相  对吗
You will be my groomsmen, though, right?
-会的  -当然
- Yeah, man. - Yeah.
-会的  -我不会错过那天的任何事
- Yeah, I mean, sure. - I wouldn't miss that day for anything.
-我当然会在  -那太棒了
- I'll be there. Of course. - It's gonna be magical.
太好了  谢谢
Great. Thanks.
那可是你的大日子
It's your day.
没想到会是这样
I didn't see that coming.
我居然把自己的笔送给他了
I can't believe I gave him my pen.
我还与他分享了家族菜谱
I can't believe I shared a family secret recipe.
我不敢相信我们输给了一个妹子
I can't believe we just got beat by a girl.
永远别再提这茬
Let's never speak of this again.
提什么
Speak of what?
嘿
Hey.
我
So, um...
你妈妈去哪了
Where's your mom?
她和阿丽克西斯出去吃晚饭了
She and Alexis went to dinner
顺便去看《油脂》的合唱版  怎么了
and a midnight sing-along of "Grease." why?
因为我准备好再战一局
'cause... i'm ready for a rematch.
你在干嘛
Why did you do that?
新游戏
New game.
我们来打扑克
Poker.
你要和我打扑克
You want to play poker against me?
脱衣扑克
Strip poker.
我马上洗牌
I'll deal.
到你了
Your bet.
我要全部押上
I think I'm gonna go all-in.
我也是
Me too.
但是我只剩这件T恤当筹码了
But...all I have left to bet with is the shirt.
我接受这个筹码
I'll take that bet.
你手上有什么牌
What do you got?
谁关心
Who cares?
这比拼字游戏好玩多了
This is so much better than scrabble.
对
Yeah!